Meet Private Artie Crawford. He’s 92¾ and he’s just gone AWOL.
The Last Rifleman is a drama, history, war film directed by Terry Loane.
A WWII veteran escapes his care home in Northern Ireland and embarks on an arduous but inspirational journey to France to
attend the 75th anniversary of the D-Day landings, finding the courage to face the ghosts of his past.
Artie Crawford, played by Pierce Brosnan.
Juliette Bellamy, played by Clémence Poésy.
Lincoln Jefferson Adams, played by John Amos.
Friedrich Mueller, played by Jürgen Prochnow.
Tom Malcolmson, played by Ian McElhinney.
Tracy Milligan, played by Tara Lynne O'Neill.
The Last Rifleman is a 2023 British drama film written by Kevin Fitzpatrick, loosely based
on real events and directed by Terry Loane, which features Pierce Brosnan.
It follows Artie Crawford (Brosnan), a Northern Irish World War II veteran who, on the 75th anniversary of the D-Day landings in Normandy, decides to secretly escape his care home and
embarks on an arduous but inspirational journey from Northern Ireland to France, to pay his final respects to his best friend and find the courage to face the ghosts of his past.
The film is loosely based on the true story of British D-Day veteran Bernard
Jordan, who left his care home in England to travel to France.
Another film based on Jordan's story, The Great Escaper, starring
Michael Caine, was released a few weeks earlier.
The Last Rifleman marked the final film appearance by John
Amos prior to his death on August 21, 2024.
The film did not have a theatrical release; it premiered on the
Sky Cinema subscription service on 5 November 2023.
The tone is emotional.